{
    "questions": [
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Chakrashila",
                "B. Bornadi",
                "C. Amchang",
                "D. Bura Chapori"
            ],
            "question": "Which of the following Wildlife Sanctuaries is located in Udalguri district",
            "answer": "B. Bornadi"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Nagaon",
                "B. Marigaon",
                "C. Dhubri",
                "D. Kamrup Metro"
            ],
            "question": "Which district ranks first in regards to density of population as per 2011 Census",
            "answer": "D. Kamrup Metro"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Bhaskar Varman",
                "B. Susthita Varman",
                "C. Harjjar Varman",
                "D. Banamala Varman"
            ],
            "question": "Hayungthal Copper Plate was issued by",
            "answer": "C. Harjjar Varman"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Prafulla Govinda Baruah",
                "B. Arup Kumar Dutta",
                "C. Joyshree Goswami Mahanta",
                "D. Dhrubajyoti Bora"
            ],
            "question": "Which of the followings is not a recepient of Padma Shri Award in 2018",
            "answer": "D. Dhrubajyoti Bora"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Bhabendra Nath Saikia",
                "B. Nabakanta Barua",
                "C. Jogesh Das",
                "D. Mahim Bora"
            ],
            "question": "Who among the following was the first recipient of the Assam Valley Literary Award",
            "answer": "A. Bhabendra Nath Saikia"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Homen Borgohain",
                "B. Nirupama Borgohain",
                "C. Rita Chowdhury",
                "D. Syed Abdul Malik"
            ],
            "question": "Who is the author of the Novel \"Astarag\"",
            "answer": "A. Homen Borgohain"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Axom Buranji",
                "B. Kachari Buranji",
                "C. Tripura Buranji",
                "D. Kamrup Buranji"
            ],
            "question": "The \"Buranji\" written by Ratna Kandali and Arjun Das Bairagee was",
            "answer": "C. Tripura Buranji"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Samata",
                "B. Davaka",
                "C. Nepala",
                "D. Kartripura"
            ],
            "question": "Which region of Assam is mentioned in the Allahabad Pillar Inscription",
            "answer": "B. Davaka"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Hadapeshvar",
                "B. Durjaya",
                "C. Jorhat",
                "D. Pragjyotishpura"
            ],
            "question": "Which one was the capital of the Mlechchha dynasty",
            "answer": "A. Hadapeshvar"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Lord Cornwallis",
                "B. Lord Wellesley",
                "C. Lord Amherst",
                "D. Lord Hastings"
            ],
            "question": "Under whose Governor-Generalship was the Treaty of Yandaboo singed",
            "answer": "C. Lord Amherst"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Katakis",
                "B. Medhis",
                "C. Talukdars",
                "D. Hazarikas"
            ],
            "question": "Which officials appointed by the Ahom king Pratap Singha, were the negotiator of \"Posa\" with the Hill Tribes",
            "answer": "A. Katakis"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Gopinath Bardoloi",
                "B. Tarunram Phukan",
                "C. Bishnuram Medhi",
                "D. Bimala Prasad Chaliha"
            ],
            "question": "Who became the first Assamese leader to have elected to the Congress Working Committee in 1926-27",
            "answer": "B. Tarunram Phukan"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Hojai",
                "B. Diphu",
                "C. Raha",
                "D. Hajo"
            ],
            "question": "The 10th annual special session of the Asam Sahitya Sabha 2019 held in",
            "answer": "C. Raha"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Salonibari",
                "B. Naharkatia",
                "C. Nazira",
                "D. Gauripur"
            ],
            "question": "The Police Training College was first established in the year 1948 at",
            "answer": "A. Salonibari"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Diphu",
                "B. Dhubri",
                "C. Dibrugarh",
                "D. Jorhat"
            ],
            "question": "The Rain Forest Research Institute in Assam is located in",
            "answer": "D. Jorhat"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Jamuna Boro",
                "B. Ankushita Boro",
                "C. Shiva Thapa",
                "D. Lovlina Borgohain"
            ],
            "question": "Who has been named in the list of athletes recommended for the prestigious Arjuna Award by the Sports Ministry'sselection committee for the year 2020",
            "answer": "D. Lovlina Borgohain"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Brahma Pala",
                "B. Ratna Pala",
                "C. Indra Pala",
                "D. Harsha Pala"
            ],
            "question": "Who is the founder of Pala Dynasty of Kamarupa Kingdom",
            "answer": "A. Brahma Pala"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Tiwa",
                "B. Kachari",
                "C. Karbi",
                "D. Bodo"
            ],
            "question": "Jongal Balahu was great ______ warrior",
            "answer": "A. Tiwa"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Lekhapani",
                "B. Margherita",
                "C. Ledo",
                "D. Tipong"
            ],
            "question": "Which Assam city is the starting point of the British built the Stillwell Road to China",
            "answer": "C. Ledo"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Digboi",
                "B. Lekhapani",
                "C. Ledo",
                "D. Margherita"
            ],
            "question": "Which one city is the headquaters of the North Eastern Coalfields",
            "answer": "D. Margherita"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 1898",
                "B. 1901",
                "C. 1902",
                "D. 1905"
            ],
            "question": "In which year, Cotton College was established",
            "answer": "B. 1901"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Sutamla",
                "B. Suklenmung",
                "C. Suhungmung",
                "D. Sujinphaa"
            ],
            "question": "Which Ahom king built the Garhgaon as the capital of the kingdom",
            "answer": "B. Suklenmung"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Pramatta Singha",
                "B. Gaurinath Singha",
                "C. Bamuni Konwar",
                "D. Jogeswar Singha"
            ],
            "question": "The Singarigharutha ceremony (traditional coronation ceremony) was first observed by which Ahom King",
            "answer": "C. Bamuni Konwar"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Rang Ghar",
                "B. Talatal Ghar",
                "C. Kareng Ghar",
                "D. Gola Ghar"
            ],
            "question": "Which one Ahom built structure is the oldest amphitheatre in Asia",
            "answer": "A. Rang Ghar"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Subinphaa",
                "B. Suteuphaa",
                "C. Sukhaangphaa",
                "D. Sukhrangpha"
            ],
            "question": "Who was the second king of Ahom kingdom",
            "answer": "B. Suteuphaa"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Domai Burhagohain",
                "B. Purnanada Burhagohain",
                "C. Ruchinath Burhagohain",
                "D. Atan Burhagohain"
            ],
            "question": "Which Burhagohain deposed Chandrakanta Singha and installed Purandar Singha in his stead",
            "answer": "C. Ruchinath Burhagohain"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 1816",
                "B. 1817",
                "C. 1818",
                "D. 1820"
            ],
            "question": "Badan Chandra Barphukan was assassinated by Rup Singh Subedar in the year",
            "answer": "C. 1818"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Tej Singha",
                "B. Kamaleswar Singha",
                "C. Jayadhwaj Singha",
                "D. Purandar Singha"
            ],
            "question": "Which Ahom King was died due to smallpox",
            "answer": "B. Kamaleswar Singha"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 1449",
                "B. 1451",
                "C. 1454",
                "D. 1455"
            ],
            "question": "Srimanta Sankardev was born in the year",
            "answer": "A. 1449"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Mir Jumla",
                "B. Husain Shah",
                "C. Nasrat Shah",
                "D. Bakhtiyar Khalji"
            ],
            "question": "The first Muslim invasion in Assam was lead by",
            "answer": "D. Bakhtiyar Khalji"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. R. F. Lodge",
                "B. T. V. Thadani",
                "C. Sarjoo Prasad",
                "D. C. P. Sinha"
            ],
            "question": "Who was the first Chief Justice of High Court of Assam ( Now known as Guwahati High Court)",
            "answer": "A. R. F. Lodge"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. S.K Dutta",
                "B. M. C. Pathak",
                "C. Holiram Deka",
                "D. C. P. Sinha"
            ],
            "question": "Who was the first Assamese Chief Justice of Guwahati High Court",
            "answer": "C. Holiram Deka"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Berry White Medical School",
                "B. St. John Medical School",
                "C. Robert Brown Medical School",
                "D. St. Patrick Medical School"
            ],
            "question": "The Assam Medical College was formerly known as",
            "answer": "A. Berry White Medical School"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 1987",
                "B. 1988",
                "C. 1990",
                "D. 1991"
            ],
            "question": "The first ever Lok Adalat at the Gauhati High Court was held in the year",
            "answer": "B. 1988"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 1872",
                "B. 1876",
                "C. 1890",
                "D. 1902"
            ],
            "question": "The Tezpur Mental Hospital was established in the year",
            "answer": "B. 1876"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Manish Deka",
                "B. Tarun Saikia",
                "C. Bidyut Bora",
                "D. Abhinandan Bora"
            ],
            "question": "Who is the first Assamese to climb Mount Everest",
            "answer": "B. Tarun Saikia"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 1869",
                "B. 1872",
                "C. 1876",
                "D. 1887"
            ],
            "question": "Jorhat Gymkhana Club which is the oldest golf course in Asia and the third oldest in the world was established in theyear",
            "answer": "C. 1876"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Guwahati",
                "B. Jorhat",
                "C. Dibrugarh",
                "D. Sivsagar"
            ],
            "question": "The first Aeroplane on North-Eastern soil was landed in which city",
            "answer": "B. Jorhat"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Joysagar",
                "B. Gaurisagar",
                "C. Rudrasagar",
                "D. None of the above"
            ],
            "question": "Which one is the largest man-made tanks in Assam",
            "answer": "A. Joysagar"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 11th",
                "B. 14th",
                "C. 15th",
                "D. 17th"
            ],
            "question": "By area wise Assam is the ________ biggest state in India",
            "answer": "D. 17th"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Kamrupa",
                "B. Pragjyotishpur",
                "C. Davaka",
                "D. Lohit"
            ],
            "question": "In the Allahabad pillar inscription, Central Assam is mentioned as",
            "answer": "C. Davaka"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Jahangir",
                "B. Shah Jahan",
                "C. Aurangzeb",
                "D. Bahadur Shah I"
            ],
            "question": "Mir Jumla who occupied Ahom capital Garhgaon was a Governor under ___________",
            "answer": "C. Aurangzeb"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Homen Borgohain",
                "B. Kanak Sen Deka",
                "C. Nagen Saikia",
                "D. Mahim Bora"
            ],
            "question": "'Atmanusandhan' is an autobiography written by",
            "answer": "A. Homen Borgohain"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Kuladhar Chaliha",
                "B. Bimala Prasad Chaliha",
                "C. Kanak Chandra Sarmah",
                "D. Krishna Nath Sarmah"
            ],
            "question": "Who was the first President of Assam Provincial Congress Committee",
            "answer": "A. Kuladhar Chaliha"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Chandradhar Barua",
                "B. Nalini Bala Devi",
                "C. Prasannalal Choudhury",
                "D. Bishnu Prasad Rabha"
            ],
            "question": "Which of the following was not a President of Assam Sahitya Sabha",
            "answer": "D. Bishnu Prasad Rabha"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Nabin Chandra Bardoloi",
                "B. Gopinath Bordoloi",
                "C. Maniram Dewan",
                "D. Radha Govinda Baruah"
            ],
            "question": "Who is also known as the \"Lion Man\" of Assam",
            "answer": "D. Radha Govinda Baruah"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Agnisnaan",
                "B. Siraj",
                "C. Firingoti",
                "D. Jeevan Baator Logori"
            ],
            "question": "Moloya Goswami wins the National Film Award for Best Actress in the Assamese film ___________",
            "answer": "C. Firingoti"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 14th",
                "B. 15th",
                "C. 16th",
                "D. 17th"
            ],
            "question": "Sarbananda Sonowal is the _______ Chief Minister of Assam",
            "answer": "A. 14th"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Jamuna",
                "B. Padma",
                "C. Meghna",
                "D. Dihang"
            ],
            "question": "Brahmaputra, after joining Tista river, is known as",
            "answer": "A. Jamuna"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Kamrup",
                "B. Nagaon",
                "C. Jorhat",
                "D. Dibrugarh"
            ],
            "question": "The first Book Fair in Assam was held at",
            "answer": "B. Nagaon"
        }
    ]
}